CHASE JOHNSTON

EMAIL: CHASEJ@LIVE.COM | PHONE: 603-703-4749

GITHUB: https://github.com/johnstoc13 | LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/chase-johnston8

PORTFOLIO: https://johnstoc13.gihub.io/Updated-Portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Website designer and multiple business owner with experience creating modern, responsive websites for small businesses and leading positive change for teenagers and young adults. Extensive experience in multitasking, teamwork, communication and problem solving in a fast paced learning environment as an air traffic controller. With my accomplishments in experience, efficiency, and teamwork, I have proven success repeatedly and look forward to using these skills in future endeavors.

APPLICATIONS

TEAM BUILDER

Front end design developer for a team-building app geared towards a remote workforce. Application was created with a team to help build teams, foster creativity, and strengthen culture in just 2 weeks!

TECH USED: Bootstrap, jQuery, Handlebars, Auth0, File Stack, Passport, mySQL, Sequelize, Heroku

CODE: https://github.com/johnstoc13/the-team-builders
DEPLOYED SITE: https://the-team-builder.herokuapp.com/

FLICK THE DECK

Flick The Deck is a fun application that combines "luck of the draw" with a faster path to movie selection based on user-selected criteria. Application is the result of a highly dynamic and cooperative team effort. I was tasked with the front end design, ensuring mobile responsiveness using Foundation CSS.

TECH USED: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Foundation, external APIs, Animate.css

CODE: https://github.com/johnstoc13/Flick-the-Deck

DEPLOYED SITE: https://johnstoc13.github.io/Flick-the-Deck/

BURGER BONANZA

This project is for all the burger lovers out there! The application allows the user to create and add burgers to a menu, where they can either eat or delete them. Yummm!

TECH USED: Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, Node, Express, MySQL, Handlebars, Heroku

CODE: https://github.com/johnstoc13/Burger-Bonanza

DEPLOYED SITE: https://chases-burger-bonanza.herokuapp.com/

EMPLOYEE TEAM GENERATOR

A simple command line application that generates a software engineering team profile web page..

TECH USED: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascipt, Node, Inquirer

 ${\tt CODE:}\ \underline{\tt https://github.com/johnstoc13/Weather-Dashboard}$

DEPLOYED SITE: https://johnstoc13.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

TECHNICAL SKILLS & ABILITIES

- HTML/CSS
- Bootstrap
- Foundation
- Javascript
- jQuery
- Moment.js
- Animate.css

- Node/Inquirer/Express
- JSON/AJAX
- Handlebars
- MySQL/Sequelize
- MongoDB/Mongoose
- Auth0/Passport/File Stack
- Heroku & Command Line

- Multitasking
- Communication
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Responsive Design
- Leading Change
- Professionalism

WORK EXPERIENCE

OWNER - GRANITE STATE STUDIO, LLC

BROOKLINE, NH - MAY 2020 - PRESENT

Owner and web designer responsible for creating fast, affordable, and responsive websites for small businesses. Oversee marketing, social media, and all other small business duties.

BUSINESS MANAGER – CHANGEMAKER TEENS, LLC

BROOKLINE, NH - JULY 2017-PRESENT

Co-owner and Business Manager for Changemaker Teens dedicated to helping teens and young adults discover a life direction that will bring purpose and meaning to their adult lives. Recently negotiated enrollment into the Finger Lakes Area Community Endowment (FLACE) allowing us to operate as a 501c3 non-profit and ensure maximum potential to improve the lives of teens throughout their community and nationwide. Currently manage all website related tasks, graphic design, sales and marketing strategies, and financial analysis.

CO-FOUNDER – J&J EVENT SERVICES, LLC BROOKLINE, NH – APRIL 2016 - JULY 2017

Co-owner and creator of company specializing in cruise charter management. Successfully negotiated cruise charter contract with a major cruise line and our client. Negotiated multiple price reductions for cabins, ensuring maximum profit potential. Also secured reservations management contract, further saving our client thousands of dollars.

AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER – FEDERAL AVIATION ADMINISTRATION NASHUA, NH – SEPTEMBER 2008-PRESENT

Radar controller responsible for the safe, orderly, and expeditious flow of traffic in some of the most congested and complicated airspace within the National Airspace System. My skills were recently showcased at a Senior Leadership Conference within the FAA as a demonstration of professionalism and safety. Certified On the Job Training Instructor responsible for training new hires. Also certified as Controller In Charge to run the operational area when assigned. Traffic Management Coordinator since 2018. Professional Standards Representative since 2017. High stress environment that allows for zero mistakes.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF NEW HAMPSHIRE - CODING BOOTCAMP - 2020

MINNEAPOLIS COMMUNITY & TECHNICAL COLLEGE – A.A.S. AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL - 2007 METROPOLITAN STATE UNIVERSITY OF DENVER – B.S. AVIATION TECHNOLOGY - 2006